Oh
Morning practice hey, uh John. Yep
You don't think lunch could have waited a little longer actually this is more like second breakfast my lunch and snacks are packed separately
I guess this is really happening
Hmm I forgot to mention this earlier, but we're taking measurements for the brochures today
So make sure you come see us as soon as school's out and tell the other first years to thanks sure
Hey
Today we'll see who's got the highest reach. I can't wait to find that out kageyama. We could even make a little wager on it, too
Three curry buns you're on
I'm starting to have my doubts about the team work
For sure wait
You
We'll be right back.
Yes, I promise we'll put it to good use.
Huh? Uh, yes, I'm single, but I'm kinda happy with where I am, so...
What's up, man?
Is there a problem?
I call these alumni, and one out of every four calls, they try to set me up with someone.
Well, good luck. So, about that video...
You're telling me you'll do it?
Hey, it's for the kids on my old team, right? I'll do whatever I can for those guys.
You ready?
I'm ready! Let's do this!
Hey, Hinata! So, how did it go?
164.2 centimeters tall! I grew 1.4 centimeters!
Whoa! That's awesome!
What about you?
Five millimeters! Now I'm 180 even!
You're in the 180s?!
And how'd you do?
181.
Point?
Point nine.
Oh, you're tall!
I win!
You win what?
I grew one more millimeter than you!
Wait a second, Hinata. You actually remember everyone's height?
Well, I guess that's good, right? At least there's one math Hinata's good at.
Comparing shrimps to pipsqueaks? How quaint.
Tsukishima! You! You!
Tsuki, you don't mean...
Whoa! You finally made it over 190, huh?
I order you to shrink!
Wish I could get as excited as them about measuring my height.
Hey, dorks! Cut that out!
Mr. Takata, you have a call in line, too.
Hi! Uh, Takata speaking. How are you?
Oh, yes. Thank you for calling. That's right.
Ah!
Tsukishima got 131.5 inches!
Wow, that's the highest so far!
Great job, Tsuki!
What are those goofballs doing?
They're measuring their vertical leap. I think it's for statistics in the Spring Nationals brochure.
Next, Nishinoya!
I guess that's pretty interesting.
Whoa! They're jumping higher than me, then!
And Nishinoya's only about 150 centimeters.
I'm 160!
118.9 inches!
Right. Kageyama, you're up.
Here I go.
Um, 132.6 inches.
That puts Kageyama at number one, then.
Yep. And just one more person to go.
Hinata, your turn.
Right!
Wow, everyone's looking at Hinata like a true rival.
Whoa!
Come on, tell us what he got!
Geez, wait a second, guys!
That's, um...
131.1!
Alright.
That's as high as you got, Asahi!
I know.
Don't remind me.
He's up five or six centimeters since the last measurement.
I guess it's different when you always want to get as high as you can.
What does that mean?
When it comes to spiking, you're just trying to get yourself as high as the ball, right?
But for Hinata, it's different.
He's absolutely positive that Kageyama will get the ball to him.
So his main goal is to jump as high as he possibly can.
I mean, we all work on our form in starting runs, and I think it's because of that all of us will improve our jumping reach.
Hmm.
And what you're saying is Kageyama's the real reason Hinata jumps that much higher.
You used to buy his gung gung yogurt for a week.
You are on!
Is everyone here?
Gather up, boys!
Okay!
Sir!
Everyone, nice work out there.
I came to tell you, I have some big news.
Kageyama.
You have been invited to participate in the National Youth Intensive!
Huh?
Wow!
That's big!
National?
Whoa!
Youth?
As in athletes under 19 years old playing for Japan itself?
Yeah, amazing.
That's just the only word I can think of.
He's just like Ushiwaka!
Ushiwaka managed to stay in the program and actually play for the team.
But there's no telling if the king will last that long.
That's so cool!
I heard that the athletes they invited to this intensive, they will be making up the pool of players who will be chosen for Japan's under 19 team in a couple of years.
They'll play against the whole world.
Out of all the 15 and 16 year olds in the country, only a handful of hopefuls are invited.
They'll get to make up the national team.
Oh, wow.
It's a pretty big deal that he even received an invitation.
Well, I guess we've been practicing with some pretty intense players then.
He's gonna play against the world.
It's a whole other level.
However, it's at the beginning of December and lasts for five days.
When we'll be training the spring nationals in January.
So you're not required to go.
I'll go!
I'm just thinking, all the best players in Japan will be there.
And besides, you already know us.
This will be a good chance to find out some new tricks.
And me?
For the national team, all Japan.
Players under 19 who will represent the whole country, understand?
Of course I do!
Well, uh, we only got an invitation for Kageyama to go, so you're out.
Well, well.
When they start hitting you up for interviews, make sure to tell them about all the things you learned from your wonderful upperclassmen Sugawara.
No.
Don't put ideas in his head.
Hey! Whatever, Suga! He needs to talk about yours truly!
Honestly, I'm just wondering why they didn't invite Nishinoya to the camp too.
I know, right?
But I guess we are kind of biased.
Well, with stuff like this, I'm sure they consider talent and potential.
But my guess is they look at how balanced a player is overall.
Mostly they'll be meeting for the first time, so they'll want team players.
And for a Libro, well...
I mean...
I think they want to ask somebody who's a bit more...
...matured.
Yeah.
Matured.
It all makes sense now.
Listen up!
I still have one more piece of news!
Also happening in the beginning of December, there will be a special training camp for promising Miyagi first years!
Coach Anabara from Jozenji High School called to tell me himself!
Apparently the idea is to try and lift the overall volleyball skills of Miyagi Prefecture as one unit.
This training camp is only open the first years.
It's a sort of quasi-youth intensive.
Quasi-intensive?
And one of our players has been invited.
Tsukishima!
Oh wow, Tsuki! Picked out of the whole prefecture!
The training camp?
Tsukishima was pretty amazing in the finals, after all.
What the hell?!
First years only?! That's crap!
Great, sir! And me?!
Well, uh...
We only got an invite for Tsuki, so...
You're out!
The Spring Nationals are right around the corner, so I'll pass.
Do your best out there, Tsukishima!
Yeah, it's not every day you get to have guys from other schools slap you around.
I get enough of that now.
Alright, I'll call back, and let both the organizers know, you guys are in!
Hey!
I'll see you from the top.
So the place for this intensive that Kageyama's going to? It's a big deal, isn't it?
It's at the Tokyo National Training Center.
Oh wow!
That's where the actual Olympic athletes go for training, right?
I would love to see the inside someday.
Well, you could probably sneak in.
Yeah, they'd arrest me on the spot.
We can all just hold down the fort here, right, Hinata?
Hold down the fort? Whatever. I mean, it's just practice.
Ah, it'll be fun.
Your legs aren't moving!
Give me another one!
Ah, come on, Kageyama! Your intensive starts tomorrow, man!
Quote!
Your legs aren't moving!
Give me another one!
Come on, Kageyama! Your intensive starts tomorrow, man!
tomorrow, man.
This is the route from Tokyo Station.
J.R. Uto?
J.R. I wonder if Kageyama got there okay?
J.R. Apparently Take wrote him some detailed directions.
J.R. He's a big boy! I'm sure he'll be fine!
J.R. I hope he gave him furigana so he can read the kanji.
J.R. Huh?
J.R. Something wrong?
J.R. Yeah. Hinata hasn't gotten here yet, has he?
J.R. Oh, not yet.
J.R. And he's usually here by now.
J.R. Uh, well, uh...
J.R. Uh...
J.R. You weren't invited, were you?
J.R. Justine.
You weren't invited, were you?
Just ignore him.
You don't know him.
He's a total stranger.
Hey, Karasuno's number 10!
Wait, Karasuno?
Oh, right, the quick attack guy.
Did he just say he wasn't invited?
How stupid are you?
Well, I really didn't want to get arrested.
What?
Oh, wow.
That's where the actual Olympic athletes go for training, right?
I would love to see the inside someday.
Well, you could probably sneak in.
Yeah, they'd arrest me on the spot.
But what in the world would ever possess you to come here?
And you mean you'd be there if they wouldn't arrest you?
How in the hell does your tiny brain work?
You stupid, stupid, stupid head!
Such a vocabulary.
I guess even big, tall four eyes can lose control every now and then.
Huh?
Apparently, Hinata snuck into the first year training camp.
So, he's at Shiratorizawa right now!
Yeah, Hinata!
Way to get yours!
That kid...
...is really asking for it.
You little...
What the hell do you think you're doing, Hinata?
Damn it!
Sorry, sir!
Wah!
Ah!
Hinata, there's a difference between being a go-getter
and a loose cannon.
I'm sorry!
That Takata fella...
He seems so mild-mannered,
but maybe he's actually terrifying.
I better be careful.
I'm not here,
because I think this will help me more than our practice will.
It's just...
This camp has so many strong players.
I want to be a part of it.
I want to see what these great players are like outside of matches.
And to see what makes them so strong.
I have to know!
I do understand that you're feeling very restless right now.
However, that doesn't excuse your actions.
You're causing problems for the camp organizers.
You need...
So, we have another ball boy around for the time being.
We can handle it.
Hm?
I made it!
Karasuno High School Volleyball Club.
That's the team that beat Ushuaka.
The Itachiyama Institute.
Giyomi Sakusa.
One of the top three Spikers in Japan.
And the only second year of the three.
And I get to watch him up close.
My name's Tobio Kageyama.
First year of Karasuno.
I'm a setter.
It's very nice to meet you.
Huh?
Yeah, sure.
Oh, man.
I'm getting so excited.
He wasn't even invited.
Is he crazy or what?
For a second there, I thought he was a middle school kid.
He sure looks like one without his jacket on.
Now that I've seen him in person, he's even smaller than I thought.
What the hell?
Fine, let the little shrimp from Karasuno stick around.
It's not like I care.
I'm gonna grind him to a pulp.
Ione-approved players are just not like the rest of us, are they?
To be honest, I had recommended Hinata for this camp.
Yes.
So if you don't mind letting him stay...
Right.
Yes.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
Talk to you.
Do you think he'll be okay?
If Coach Washijo didn't want him there, he would have made that clear to everyone.
Looking at this roster, Washijo is definitely in charge of this thing.
Doesn't look to me like the old man has changed a bit.
Simple is best.
He loves height and power.
And he's always got his feelers out, looking for strong players to recruit.
I don't know how far Hinata has thought this through, but...
This could be a really important opportunity for the kid, still.
Well...
I mean, personally, I couldn't have asked for anything better.
Let me just say this.
Without the play of your personal setter, Kageyama, I don't see you as being worth anything.
If you don't like being a ball boy, you're welcome to go home at any time.
This might be far more grueling for Hinata than he realizes.
The floor's not hardwood.
See that screen?
It's constantly showing footage from down here on the courts with a six-second delay.
That way, you can examine all of your plays in detail.
That's awesome!
Gather round.
Now then, this is our men's Olympic team coach.
His name is Hiberita.
Would you mind giving the boys a pep talk?
Oh, sure.
Well, I'm sure you're all pretty tired of hearing us old guys, so I'll keep it short.
I'm sure you've all heard, Japan crumbles before height and power.
That was the old saying, but it's outdated now.
The qualities you have aren't things you show off on the outside.
They're things you bring out from the inside.
When you're up against the world, give them a good fight.
So let's prove to everyone there's more to volleyball than the eye test.
Gather up, everyone!
I'm very sorry for interrupting practice.
I'm a first-year from Kurasuno High School, Shouyo Hirata.
I'm 164 centimeters tall.
My position is Bow Boy!
Thank you for having me!
Hey...
I see.
Hello man!
Transcription by CastingWords
Egoist, what is that?
I don't have a reason to win
I can't be able to win
I don't have a chance to win
We are!
Why?
Next time, Lost.